Guide to the George B. Dantzig Papers
Stanford University Libraries.
Dept. of Special Collections & University Archives.
George B. Dantzig papers
1937-1999
SC0826
Dantzig, George Bernard, 1914-2005.
89.25 Linear feet
Dept. of Special Collections & University Archives. Stanford University Libraries. 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: speccollref@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Information about Access
The materials are open for research use. Audio-visual materials are not available in original format, and must be reformatted to a digital use copy.
Biographical/Historical note
George Bernard Dantzig (November 8, 1914 – May 13, 2005) was an American mathematical scientist who made important contributions to operations research, computer science, economics, and statistics.
Dantzig is known for his development of the simplex algorithm, an algorithm for solving linear programming problems, and his work with linear programming. In statistics, Dantzig solved two open problems in statistical theory, which he had mistaken for homework after arriving late to a lecture of Jerzy Neyman.
Dantzig was the Professor Emeritus of Transportation Sciences and Professor of Operations Research and of Computer Science at Stanford.
Born in Portland, Oregon, George Bernard Dantzig was named after George Bernard Shaw, the Irish writer. His father, Tobias Dantzig, was a Baltic German mathematician and linguist, and his mother, Anja Dantzig (née Ourisson), was a French linguist. Dantzig's parents met during their study at the Sorbonne University in Paris, where Tobias studied mathematics under Henri Poincaré, after whom Dantzig's brother was named. The Dantzigs immigrated to the United States, where they settled in Portland, Oregon.
Early in the 1920s the Dantzig family moved from Baltimore to Washington. His mother became a linguist at the Library of Congress, and his father became a math tutor at the University of Maryland, College Park, George attended Powell Junior High School and Central High School; one of his friends there was Abraham Seidenberg, who also became a professional mathematician. By the time he reached high school he was already fascinated by geometry, and this interest was further nurtured by his father, challenging him with complicated problems, particularly in projective geometry.
George Dantzig earned bachelor's degrees in mathematics and physics from the University of Maryland in 1936, and his master's degree in mathematics from the University of Michigan in 1938. After a two-year period at the Bureau of Labor Statistics, he enrolled in the doctoral program in mathematics at the University of California, Berkeley, where he studied statistics under Jerzy Neyman.
With the outbreak of World War II, George took a leave of absence from the doctoral program at Berkeley to join the U.S. Air Force Office of Statistical Control. In 1946, he returned to Berkeley to complete the requirements of his program and received his Ph.D. that year. Although he had a faculty offer from Berkeley, he returned to the Air Force as mathematical advisor to the comptroller.
In 1952 Dantzig joined the mathematics division of the RAND Corporation. By 1960 he became a professor in the Department of Industrial Engineering at UC Berkeley, where he founded and directed the Operations Research Center. In 1966 he joined the Stanford faculty as Professor of Operations Research and of Computer Science. A year later, the Program in Operations Research became a full-fledged department. In 1973 he founded the Systems Optimization Laboratory (SOL) there. On a sabbatical leave that year, he headed the Methodology Group at the International Institute for Applied Systems Analysis (IIASA) in Laxenburg, Austria. Later he became the C. A. Criley Professor of Transportation Sciences at Stanford, and kept going, well beyond his mandatory retirement in 1985.
He was a member of the National Academy of Sciences, the National Academy of Engineering, and the American Academy of Arts and Sciences. George was the recipient of many honors, including the first John von Neumann Theory Prize in 1974, the National Medal of Science in 1975, an honorary doctorate from the University of Maryland, College Park in 1976. The Mathematical Programming Society honored Dantzig by creating the George B. Dantzig Prize, bestowed every three years since 1982 on one or two people who have made a significant impact in the field of mathematical programming.
Dantzig died on May 13, 2005, in his home in Stanford, California, of complications from diabetes and cardiovascular disease. He was 90 years old.
Access Terms
Computer science--Research; Computer science--Study and teaching; Mathematicians--United States.; Mathematics --Study and teaching (Higher).; Systems programming (Computer science)
Collection Contents
- Additional material, Accession ARCH-2005-363
  - On a Class of Distributions that Approach the Normal Distribution Function, 1939 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - On the Non-Existence of Tests of Students' Hypothesis Involving Power Functions Independent of Sigma, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - A Theorem on Linear Inequalities, 1948, January 5 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - A Proof of the Equivalence of the Programming Problem and the Game Problem, in T.C. Koopmans (ed.) (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Programming of Interdependent Activities, II: Mathematical Model, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Maximization of a Linear Function of VariablesSubject to Linear Inequalities (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Application of the Simplex Method to the Transportation Problem, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Programming in a Linear Structure, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Linear Programming, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - On the Fundamental Lemma of Neyman and Pearson, 1591 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - The Generalized Simplex Method for Minimizing a Linear Form Under Linear Inequality Constraints, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - The Fixed Charge Problem, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - A Duality Theorem Based on the Simplex Method, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Alternate Algorithm for the Revised Simplex Method Using Product Form for the Inverse, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - The Dual Simplex Algorithm (Notes on Linear Programming Part VII), 1954 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Upper Bounds, Secondary Constraints, and Block Triangularity in Linear Programming (Notes on Linear Programming: Part VIII, XI, X), 1954 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Notes on Linear Programming: Part XI, Composite Simplex-Dual Simplex Algorithm, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Solution for a Large-Scale Traveling Salesman Problem, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Minimizing the Number of Tankers to Meet a Fixed Schedule, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - The Product Form for the Inverse in the Simplex Method, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - A Comment on Eddie's "Traffic Delays at Toll Booths", 1954 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Linear Programming Under Uncertainty, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Optimal Solution of a Dynamic Leontief Model with Substitution (Notes on Linear Programming: Part XIII), 1955 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - A Production Smoothing Problem, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Developments in Linear Programming, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Constructive Proof of the Min-Max Theorem, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Recent Advances in Linear Programming, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - On the Max-Flow Min-Cut Theorems of Networks, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Formulating a Linear Programming Model, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 28a)
  - Computation of Maximal Flows in Networks, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 28b)
  - Concepts, Origins and Uses of Linear Programming, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - A Primal-Dual Algorithm for Linear Programs, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Note on Klein's "Direct Use of Extremal Principles in Solving Certain Problems Involving Inequalities", 1956 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Thoughts on Linear Programming and Automation, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Discrete Variable Extremum Problems, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - On the Status of Multi-Stage Linear Programs, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Solving Two-Move Games with Perfect Information, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - On Integer and Partial Integer Linear Programming Problems, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - A Linear Programming Approach to the Chemical Equilibrium Problem, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Chemical Equilibrium in Complex Mixtures, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 37a)
  - Note on Solving Linear Programs in Integers, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Dilworth's Theorem on Partially Ordered Sets, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - On a Linear Programming Combinatorial Approach to the Traveling Salesman Problem, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - The Allocation of Aircraft to Routes - An Example of Linear Programming Under Uncertain Demand, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Optimum Routing of Gasoline Delivery Trucks, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - The Truck Dispatching Problem, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Inductive Proof of the Simplex Method, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - On the Shortest Route Through a Network, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - On the Significance of Solving Linear Programming with Some Integer Variables, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - General Convex Objective Forms, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - A Machine-Job Scheduling Model, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Computing Tetraethyl-Lead Requirements in a Linear-Programming Format, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - A Mathematical Model of the Respiratory System, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Solving the Chemical Equilibrium Problem Using the Decomposition Principle, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - A Mathematical Model of the Chemistry of the External Respiratory System, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - On the Solution of the Two-Staged Linear Programs Under Uncertainty, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - Decomposition Principle for Linear Programs, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - Future Developments of Operations Research, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - A Mathematical Model of the Human External Respiratory System, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - Quadratic Programming- A Variant of the…Algorithms, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - On the Reduction of Certain Multiplicative Chemical Equilibrium Systems to Mathematically Equivalent Additive Systems, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - A Proof of a Property of Leontief and Markov Matrices, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - Compact Basis Triangularization for the Simplex Method, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 60)
  - Symmetric Dual Nonlinear Programs, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 61)
  - Linear Programming in a Markov Chain, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 62)
  - Molecular-Sized Channels and Flows Against the Gradient, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 63)
  - Positive (Semi-) Definite Matrices and Mathematical Programming, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 64)
  - Maximum Payloads per Unit Time Delivered Through an Air Network, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 65)
  - Linear Programming and Extensions, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 66)
  - A Model for Sodium-Potassium Transport in Red Cells, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 67)
  - Automated Multiphasic Screening and Diagnosis, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 68)
  - New Mathematical Methods in the Life Sciences, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 69)
  - Generalized Upper Bounded Techniques for the Linear Programming- I, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 70)
  - Generalized Upper Bounded Techniques for the Linear Programming- II, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 71)
  - Research Problems, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 72)
  - Linear Control Processes and Mathematical Programming, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 73)
  - Updating the Product Form of the Inverse for the Revised Simplex Method, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 74)
  - Operations Research in the World of Today and Tomorrow, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 75)
  - Large-Scale System Optimization: A Review, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 76)
  - Optimization in Operations Research, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 77)
  - The Simplex Method, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 78)
  - On the Continuity of the Minimum Set of a Continuous Function, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 79)
  - On Steady-State Intercompartamental Flow, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 80)
  - Optimal Assignment of Computer Storage by Chain Decomposition of Partially Ordered Sets, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 81)
  - Linear Programming and its Progeny, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 82)
  - An Integer Branching Algorithm for Locating Warehouses, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 82a)
  - Finding a Cycle in a Graph with Minimum Cost to Time Ratio with Application to a Ship Routing Problem, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 83)
  - All Shortest Routes From a Fixed Origin in a Graph, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 84)
  - All Shortest Routes in a Graph, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 85)
  - On Positive Principal Minors, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 86)
  - Complementary Pivot Theory of Mathematical Programming, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 87)
  - Mathematical Programming Language, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 88)
  - Integral Extreme Points, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 89)
  - Large-Scale Linear Programming, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 90)
  - A Generalization of the Linear Complimentarity Problem, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 91)
  - Sparse Matrix Techniques in Two Mathematical Programming Codes, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 92)
  - Complementary Spanning Trees, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 93)
  - A Hospital Admission Problem, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 94)
  - Existence of A-Avoiding Paths in Abstract Polytopes, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 95)
  - On a Model for Computing Round-Off Error of a Sum, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 96)
  - Natural Gas Transmission System Optimization, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 97)
  - A Control Problem of Bellman, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 98)
  - MPL: Mathematical Programming Language Specification Manual for Committee Review, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 99)
  - Generalized Upper Bounding Techniques, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 100)
  - Generalized Linear Programming, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 100a)
  - Maximum Diameter of Abstract Polytopes, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 101)
  - Existence of X-Paths in Abstract Polytopes, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 102)
  - On the Need for a Systems Optimization Laboratory, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 103)
  - Fourier-Motzkin Elimination and Its Dual, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 104)
  - Health Care in Future Cities, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 105)
  - On the Relation of Operations Research to Mathematics, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 106)
  - The ORSA New Orleans Address on Compact City, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 107)
  - The Price Lecture on Compact City, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 108)
  - The User's Guide to MPL/T.1 (Revised), 1972 (Box 3, Folder 109)
  - Solving Staircase Linear Programs by a Nested Block-Angular Method, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 110)
  - A Complementary Algorithm for an Optimal Capital Path with Invariant Proportions, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 111)
  - Drews' Institutionalized Divvy Economy, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 112)
  - On a Convex Programming Problem of Rozanov, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 113)
  - Optimization, Mathematical Theory of (Linear and Nonlinear Programming), 1974 (Box 3, Folder 114)
  - Dygam- A Computer System for the Solution of Dynamic Programs, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 115)
  - Determining Optimal Policies for Ecosystems, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 116)
  - On the Reduction of an Integrated Energy and Interindustry Model to a Smaller Linear Program, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 117)
  - Formulating a PILOT Model for Energy in Relation to the National Economy, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 118)
  - On a PILOT Linear Programming Model for Assessing Physical Impact on the Economy of a Changing Energy Picture, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 119)
  - Note on the Objective Function for the PILOT Model, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 120)
  - NO DOCUMENTS (Box 3, Folder 121)
  - Solution of a Large Scale Airforce Ordnance Planning Problem by Mathematical Programming, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 122)
  - An Algorithm for a Piecewise Linear Model of Trade and Production with Negative Prices and Bankruptcy, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 123)
  - Linear Programming: Its Past and Its Future, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 124)
  - PILOT Model for Assessing Energy-Economic Options, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 125)
  - Determining Prices and Monetary Flows of the PILOT Energy Model, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 126)
  - Energy Models and Large-Scale Systems Optimization, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 127)
  - NO DOCUMENTS (Box 3, Folder 128)
  - Large-Scale Systems Optimization with Application to Energy, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 129)
  - Discovering Hidden Totally Leontief Substitution Systems, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 130)
  - Stanford PILOT Energy/Economic Model, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 131)
  - Stanford PILOT Energy/Economic Model, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 131a)
  - At the Interface of Modeling and Algorithms Research, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 132)
  - Quantitative Evaluation of Pest Management Options: The Spruce Budworm Case Study, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 133)
  - Are Dual Variables Prices? If Not, How to Make them More So, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 134)
  - A Basic Factorization Method for Block Triangular Linear Programs, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 135)
  - Linear Optimal Control Problems and Generalized Linear Programming, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 136)
  - Computational Experience with a Continuous Network Design Code, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 137)
  - Formulating and Solving the Network Design Problem by Decomposition, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 138)
  - Pricing Underemployed Capacity in a Linear Economic Model, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 139)
  - Framework for a System of Transportation Spatial Form Research Tools, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 140)
  - The Role of Models in Determining Policy for Transition to a More Resilient Technological Society, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 141)
  - Comments on Khachian's Algorithims for Linear Programming, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 142)
  - Expected Number of Steps of the Simplex Method for a Linear Program with a Convexity Constraint, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 143)
  - Large-Scale Linear Programing, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 144)
  - Stanford PILOT Engineering Model, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 145)
  - Concerns About Large-Scale Models, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 146)
  - 143, October 1998 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - 144, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - 145, 5/23/1978 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - 146, April 1982 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - 147 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - 148 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Reminscences about the origin of LP, 9/81 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - 149 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - 150 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - 151 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - 152 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - 153 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - 154, March 1982 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - 155 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - 156, August 1982 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - 157 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - 158, November 1983 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - 159 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - 160, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - 161 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - 162, June 1985 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - 163 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - The New Palgrave - "Linear Programming" article 164 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - 165 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - 167, Apil 1986 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - 166, Janurary 1987 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Not labeled (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - 167 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - 168 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - 169 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - 170, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - 171, February 1988 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Misc. (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - 172, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - 173, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - 174, June 1988 (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - 175, September 1988 (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - 176, December 1987 (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - 177 (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - 178 (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - 179 (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - 180 (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - 181 (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - 182, March 1991 (Box 4, Folder 44)
  - 183 (Box 4, Folder 45)
  - 184, August 1991 (Box 4, Folder 46)
  - 185, 10/17/1994 (Box 4, Folder 47)
  - 186 (Box 4, Folder 48)
  - 187 (Box 4, Folder 49)
  - 188 (Box 4, Folder 50)
  - 189 (Box 4, Folder 51)
  - 190 (Box 4, Folder 52)
  - 191 (Box 4, Folder 53)
  - 192 (Box 4, Folder 54)
  - 193 (Box 4, Folder 55)
  - 194 (Box 4, Folder 56)
  - 195 (Box 4, Folder 57)
  - Papers about Exhibits, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Graphical Material on George B. Dantzig, 1982 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Steve Yuke, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Operations Research Program Library Linear Programming System, 1981 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - An Algorithm for a Piecewise linear model of trade…Bankruptcy. With Eaves-Gale; submitted to: Math Programming, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Tahoe Conference, Jul-65 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Korea, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Paris, July 18-22, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Math Modelleny St. Louis, Aug 47, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - China, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - "Impact" - Comp in Math @SU, Jul-86 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Israel, Jun-85 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Expense Reports, G.B. Dantzig, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - MIT Math. Programming Symposium, August 5-9, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - New Zealand, Aug-85 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Plenary Speaker Adelaide, Australia, Aug-85 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - NAE Annual Meeting Washington, DC (CANCEL), October 2-3 1985 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - AM. ACAD. Cambridge, MA, Nov. 19-20, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Israel, Dec-85 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - ONR/Monterey (J.A. Tomlin organizing), Feb. 20-21 1985 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - NAS Roundtable, San Francisco, 31-Jan-86 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - CS Forum, February 4-6, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Halifax (Dempster), Mar 31-April 2, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - China, Sep-85 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Urbana, Univ of Illinois, Fall 1983 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Texas: R. Chandrasekaran, 1983 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - S. Kim; Korea, 1982 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - AMS lecture Don Albers, Menlo College, 23-Feb-85 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - NAS Roundtable, UC- Berkeley, 1-Feb-85 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - CEPR Energy Workshop, Peerage, Feb 22-23, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Sym on Economics and Technology, March 17-19, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - AA Council:, 10-Apr-85 (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - NBER/Stanford Shoven (Workshop, applied gen. equil), April 12-13, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - IBM Yorktown Heights, May 1-10, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - ORSA/TIMS: Boston, April 29-May1, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - Princeton, 2-May-85 (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - IIASA, Jun-85 (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - Japan, Oct-82 (Box 5, Folder 38)
  - Russia Trip - Comments on Trip, Jun-73 (Box 5, Folder 39)
  - Invitations - Decline, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 40)
  - England Silver Medal, Sep-86 (Box 5, Folder 41)
  - Prague, Sep-86 (Box 5, Folder 42)
  - IBM, San Jose, 5-Sep-86 (Box 5, Folder 43)
  - American Academy: Council Meeting: Cambridge, MA, Nov. 11-12, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 44)
  - IBM - Ellis Johnson, Dec. 15-19, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 45)
  - GBD Lecture: Econ, March 6,1986 (Box 5, Folder 46)
  - Philidelphia (J. Bloom), April 3-4, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 47)
  - Amer. Academy Council Meeting - Cambridge MA, 9-Apr-86 (Box 5, Folder 48)
  - Cottle, Workshop@Stanford, April 17-18, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 49)
  - Applied General Equilibrium Workshop @NBER, SU, April 18-19, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 50)
  - Southern California Gas, 6-May-86 (Box 5, Folder 51)
  - Carnegie-Mellon Honorary Degree, May 1986 (Box 5, Folder 52)
  - Shell Oil, Houston, 11-Jun-86 (Box 5, Folder 53)
  - Shell, Houston, June 10-11, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 54)
  - ORSA/TIMS: Los Angeles, April 14-16, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 55)
  - D. Klingman - Austin, Texas, April 20-21, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 56)
  - Jim Ho - University of Tennessee, May 13-14, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 57)
  - Minneapolis (Rosen), May 16-18, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 58)
  - Washington ORSA/TIMS, April 25-27, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 59)
  - Amer. Acad.; Council Meeting, April 6-8, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 60)
  - RAND, Santa Monica, 14-Nov-88 (Box 5, Folder 61)
  - Israel, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 62)
  - Math Dev. Arising from LP, June 25-July, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 63)
  - Rutgers, 18-May-87 (Box 5, Folder 64)
  - Austin, TX, May-87 (Box 5, Folder 65)
  - Princeton (Golub), May 13-15, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 66)
  - Tokyo: MPS, Aug-88 (Box 5, Folder 67)
  - Leadership Seminar College of Notre Dame, Belmont, 11-Jun-88 (Box 5, Folder 68)
  - ORSA, Williamsburg, January 4-6, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 69)
  - San Jose State, 23-Apr-87 (Box 5, Folder 70)
  - Asilomar/IBM "Progress in Math. Prog.", March 1-4, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 71)
  - Madison, Aug 10-12, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 72)
  - Equilibrium Cont. Shoven; NBER, May 1-2, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 73)
  - England Silver Medal, 6-Jul-87 (Box 5, Folder 74)